Okay. So, what I've shown you before is
a nice like rosy way of looking at
things. Um, but sometimes things don't
always work out quite as smoothly as
we'd like. So, um, what I've done here
is I added this function here called
divide. Um, if you don't know how to
write a function like that, um, I'd
recommend looking at a previous video.
But um in this video, I've written the
divide function and I'm ready to push
that up to GitHub. So I published my
branch and now I'm going to create a
pull request. Down here it says I cannot
automatically merge. Says don't worry,
you can still create the pull request.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to
hit create pull request.
And now I am here. And it says you can't
automatically merge. Don't worry, you
can still create the pull request. So,
I'm going to go ahead and create this
pull request.
And it says the branch has conflicts
that must be resolved. Use the web
editor or command line to resolve the
conflicts before moving on. In other
words, my code contradicts code that is
in the main branch. So, what I'm going
to do is I'm going to click this resolve
conflicts. This happened because another
account created this function called
divide. So, we edited the same lines of
code and now GitHub doesn't know which
one is correct. So, I've got my line
here and their lines are here.
So, this is my change. This is their
change. I'm going to move my picture a
little bit so we can see the rest of
this. So, to handle this, all you do is
you compare the lines of code. So
everything between the equal sign and
the arrows is what's on the main copy of
our code. Everything between the equal
sign and the other arrows is the copy
that we're bringing in. So the question
is, do we want to keep our code or the
other code? If you want to keep both,
then you totally can. So you could have
two divide functions. Well, you probably
don't want two divide functions, but you
could keep both lines of code. So maybe
this isn't actually a conflict and you
want both lines of code. If you do that,
you'll accept both changes. In this
case, because these are written using
lambda syntax, I want to keep the
incoming change because that's written
with lambda syntax. So I'm going to
click accept incoming change.
Whoops. Going to hit control Z. I'm
going to accept the current change. It's
marked right next to it which one is
which. So I'm going to accept the
current change. and that will get my
correct function. And then I will mark
this as resolved. And then because I'm
resolving conflicts and I've changed
something about my code, I now have to
make a new commit. So I'm going to click
this commit merge.
And once it's done, I have now removed
any conflicts between my copy of code
and the main copy of code. Now I can
merge this pull request. So we'll merge
the pull request.
And now if we look at the live code um
here in multiply.js we have multiply add
and divide. So even though my code
conflicted with code that was already
there um we were able to just go into
the resolve editor and find the code
that we wanted to keep and the code that
we didn't want to keep and we were able
to merge them together. And that is how
you deal with a conflict in GitHub. It's
not normally that clean. Normally takes
a lot of work. You probably have to talk
to a lot of other people if you're
working with other people to figure out
why your code is conflicting and which
code should be kept. Um but the process
for resolving it um can be done in the
GitHub online editor.